Guide to the Richard Bruce Nugent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1941-1987; Series I; (17 boxes)
  - Schlick, Robert, 1942-1948; 5 Letters, 1 Invitation (Box 13)
    1 of the letters is a cover letter addressed to Nugent's mother asking her to forward the enclosed letter to Nugent. Schlick was a minor poet. Homosexual content.
  - Sherry, Paul (Council for Higher Education, United Church of Christ), 1966; 1 Letter (Box 13)
  - Singleton, Norma Jean, 1974; 1 Letter, 1 Card (Box 13)
  - Smith, Michael (BWMT), 1982; 1 Letter, 1 Note. Enclosures (Box 14)
  - Spady, James G., 1972; 1 Letter (Box 14)
  - Steinberg, Adeline, 1961-1966; 1 Letter, 2 Cards (Box 14)
    One card includes a photo of Steinberg.
  - Steppingstones (James B. Gwynne), 1983; 1 Letter with Enclosures (Box 14)
  - Taylor, Billy, 1969; 1 Letter (Box 14)
  - Taylor, Cyril, 1946; 1 Letter (Box 14)
  - Thompson, James W. (Abba Elethea), 1976-1986; 8 Letters, 5 Cards, 1 Flyer, Enclosures (Box 14)
    Enclosures: Newapaper articles about Thompson, Newspaper articles about Detroit artist LeRoy Foster, 1 poem typescript, brochure for "Elethea's Contour Centre
  - Thompson, James W. (Abba Elethea)--Nugent Letters to, 1970--1977; ca 33 Letters (Box 15)
    Xerox copies of letters from RBN in the files of James W. Thompson
  - Tignor, Eleanor, 1983; 1 Letter (Box 15)
  - Tomorrow's Man, 1957; 1 Letter (Box 15)
    Editor declines to print Nugent drawings
  - Tucker, Marian, 1969; 2 Postcards (Box 15)
  - Turchio, Lou, 1947; 1 Letter, 1 Card with Wedding Photo (Box 15)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1936-1948; 3 Letters, 4 CVV Photo Postcards, 1 Christmas Card, 1 Xerox copy (Box 15)
    The CVV photo postcards depict Arturo Nanna, a young man in profile, an African American holding his young son (both in IBPOEW uniforms), and a statue (Danish or Norwegian?) of a sexy, thick-legged nearly nude youth.
  - Vetturini, 1975; 2 Unsent Letters from RBN (Box 15)
  - Voci, Ara & Andrew, 1 Christmas Card (Box 15)
  - Wagner, Martin ("Marty), 1953-1977; 14 Letters, 1 Envelope (Box 15)
    One of the letters is an unsent letter from RBN to Wagner.
  - Walker, Dell, 1973; 1 Letter (Box 15)
  - Wall, Cheryl, 1986; 1 Letter (Box 15)
  - Weed, Eunice, 1976-1987 (Box 15)
    11 Cards, 1 Note, 1 Envelope Eunice Weed was an old friend of Bernard Kay
  - Weiss, Burton, 1985; 1 Letter (Box 15)
    Weiss is a rare book dealer.
  - Wessels, Garritt, 1971-1976; 35 Letters, 2 Cards, 1 Telegram (Box 16)
    Wessels was a South African friend whom Nugent met in Rome.
  - Westbrook, Rene, 1983; 4 Letters (Box 16)
  - White, Kay, 1947; 1 Card (Box 16)
  - Wirth, Thomas, 1 Letter with enclosure, 1 Card (Box 16)
    The card incorporates an original Nugent drawing. The enclosure relates to Nugent's April 4, 1982, interview for Hatch-Billops's Artists and Influences
  - Zagrando, Robert, 1982; 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - Zion, Anne, 3 Letters, 1 Note, 4 Cards, 1 Telegram (Box 16)
    One of the letters is an unfinished, unsent letter to Zion from Nugent
  - --------, Arturo, 1945; 1 Postcard, 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - --------, Benji, 1980; 9 Letters (Box 16)
    Benji was a mutual friend of Nugent and Raymond Jenkins
  - --------, Burton, 1948; 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - --------, Charlie, 1946; 11 Letters (Box 16)
    Charlie was a soldier
  - --------, Faith, 1 Birthday Card/Note (Box 16)
  - --------, Gene, 1946-1948; 23 Letters, 1 Postcard, 1 Photograph, 1 odd page (Box 16)
    Gene was a soldier stationed in Virginia & Germany.
  - -------, Harold, 1948; 1 Postcard (Box 16)
  - --------, Joe, 1944; 4 Letters (Box 16)
    Joe was in the Army Air Force. One of the letters is from RBN to Joe (unsent). It includes small drawings of RBN's cats
  - --------, Lang, 1972; 1 Postcard (Box 16)
  - --------, Leon, ca 1953; 1 Letter (Box 16)
    First page of an unsent letter from RBN to Leon
  - --------, Louie, 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - --------, Louis, 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - --------, Mario, 1972; 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - --------, Mary (?), 1978; 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - --------, Paul, 1 Letter (Box 16)
  - --------, Sol, 1944; 1 Letter (Box 16)
    Sol is a soldier
  - --------, Tony, 1 Postcard (Box 16)
  - --------, -------- ("Laughing Boy"), 1963; 2 Postcards (Box 16)
  - --------, -------, 8 Items (Box 16)
  - Fragments & Notes (Box 16)
  - D'Ambrosio, Antonio, 1972-1979; ca 100 Leaves (Box 17)
    Letters to D'Ambrosio, fragments, notes
- Poems, short works of fiction and nonfiction, interviews, 1920s-1985; Series II; (10 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes miscellanous notes and notebooks.
  - BEFORE STONEWALL Interview with Jewelle Gomez, Typewritten Transcript (9 pp.) (Box 18)
    Xerox copy of the transcript.
  - IN THE LIFE Interview with Charles Michael Smith, Sept 1, 1985; Typewritten transcript with corrections (16 pp.) Xerox copy. (Box 18)
  - GEISHA MAN Notebooks, ca 1927; 2 Stenographic Notebooks (Box 18)
  - GEISHA MAN Manuscript, ca 1927; 12 pp. Holograph Manuscript (Box 18)
    Titled "Kandy". In pencil. Paper age-tanned but sound. Some corners folded over, a few edge chips & tears.
  - Notebook 1, ca 1929; 1 Stenographic Notebook (Box 18)
  - Notebook 2, 1 Stenographic Notebook with "Wire-O" binding (Box 18)
    Holograph entries: Poem about Harlem "To Rose" 3 pp. Notes for a man-boy love story laid in. 1 p. Front cover rippled with damp; first two pages stained.
  - Poem: " Why Do I love the moon, 1 Leaf (Box 18)
    Holograph on yellow lined paper.
  - Poems 1, 6 Leaves (Box 18)
  - Poems 2, 12 Leaves (Box 18)
  - Poems and Songs, 14 leaves (Box 18)
  - Song: "Live to Learn to Love, 1 Leaf (Box 18)
    Holograph. Chipped and stained.
  - Poems 3, 8 Leaves (Box 18)
  - Poem: "You Think to Shame Me, 6 Leaves (Box 18)
    Incomplete. First page stained, else very good.
  - Song: "Which is the Way That Jesus Comes?" (title supplied), ca 1928; "1 Leaf " (Box 18)
    Holograph rhyme on the stationery of the Hotel Trenier, Chicago.
  - Infants of the Spring, 1 Leaf (Box 18)
    Holograph copy in Nugent's hand of the letter to Gabriel D' Annunzio from Paul Arbian that appears on p. 223 of Wallace Thurman's novel Infants of the Spring. Paper yellowed. Right edge chipped and frayed. In a polyester folder.
  - Poems 4 (Humorous), 7 Leaves (Box 18)
  - Poem: "Three Love Songs Learned from Life in Venezuela, 4 Leaves (Box 18)
    Edges age-tanned, else very good.
  - Story: "Melvin, 10 Leaves (Box 18)
    Incomplete typescript, together with 1 page of an earlier version. Holograph corrections in Nugent's hand.
  - Paupaulekejo: A Three-Act Play by Georgia Douglas Johnson & Bruce Nugent, 1920s; 17 leaves (Box 18)
    Complete typescript. Overall very good condition. Unpublished.
  - Story: "The Bartender, 5 Leaves (Box 18)
    Paper fragile and badly age-tanned. Edges chipped, with loss of text in the last line of two of the pages.
  - Story: "Lavendar Ladies: An Echo of the Mauve Decade by Richard Bruce and Noel Deloraine, 30 Leaves (Box 18)
    Holograph notes and partial manuscript on lined notebook paper. Incomplete. Paper age-tanned but otherwise in very good condition.
  - Story: "Noel" [Title supplied], 5 Leaves. (Box 18)
    Apparently incomplete holograph manuscript on lined 2-hole notebook paper. A quasi-autobiographical fragment from Nugent's childhood.
  - Cat Girl [Story]; The Winds Hold Their Breath [poem], ca 1925; 4 Holograph Leaves (Box 18)
  - Story: "If There's Anything I Can't Stand It's A Faggot" [Title supplied], 3 Leaves (Box 19)
    Holograph manuscript on lined 2-hole notebook paper. Stained.
  - The Creation [Play, title supplied], 23-Leaves (5.5" x 8.5") (Box 19)
    Holograph manuscript together with a 4-leaf typescript (incomplete), with a carbon, of the first part of the play. The carbon has an addition in Nugent's hand.
  - Autobiographical Fragment: Birth of Baby Sister, 4 Leaves (Box 19)
    2 2-page typescripts. Two versions of the same narrative.
  - Half High (Novella) Folder 1, 108 Leaves (Box 19)
  - Half High (Novella) Folder 2, 58 Leaves (Box 19)
    Typescript, 7+ 54 pp., missing pp. 22-24, with a holograph insert after p. 21. Ribbon copy. Apparently a later version, with minor changes. Includes half-titles, dedication page, contents, etc.
  - Half High (Novella) Folder 3, 2 Leaves (Box 19)
    1 page of "Notes to be used (perhaps) in Half-High" and 1 page from an early typescript.
  - Notebook 3 -- "Pope Pius the Only, 21-Leaf Spiral Composition Book (Box 19)
    Contains an incomplete holograph version of the story "Pope Pius the Only". Also "Dear Diary", with 22 arty one-paragraph entries. (Also notes on French lessons.)
  - Pope Pius the Only, 5 Leaves (Box 19)
    Typescript. Pages age-tanned, corners chewed.
  - Colonial Worthies Folder 1, 64 Leaves (Box 19)
    Typescript, carbon copy. Short narratives (1-3 pp. each) of 17th-century inhabitants of New Amsterdam. Contains genealogical data and material from court records. Written in the employ of the WPA. Fragile, acidic paper, heavily age-tanned.
  - Colonial Worthies Folder 2, 28 Leaves (Box 19)
    Continuation of Folder 1.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Harlem, 15 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript ribbon copy. Fragile & acidic paper, heavily age-tanned, with edges chipped & corners missing on some pages.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Alexander Gumby, 1939; 4 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript carbon copy. Fragile & acidic paper, heavily age-tanned.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On The Dark Tower, 4 Leaves (one of which is supplied in facsimile) (Box 20)
    Typescript carbon copy. Fragile & acidic paper, heavily age-tanned. Page 4 is missing and supplied in facsimile from the microfilm copy in the Schomburg (WPA Writers Project, Reel 1).
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Arthur (Happy ) Rhone, 4 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Concerning Thomas J. Wansley, Pirate, 2 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): On 'Gloria Swanson'/ Real Name Mr. Winston, 3 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Marshall's: A Portrait, 1944; 10 Leaves (Box 20)
    2 typescript carbon copies, each 5 pp. One is stamped "By Richard Bruce Nugent/Agent: Warren Marr II...
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Comments on and by Cecil Beaton (Not Harlem), 6 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript carbon copy. Acidic paper, age-tanned.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Juano Hernandez, 4 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Gouldtown, 6 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript carbon copy. Acidic paper, age-tanned (3 leaves). In addition, 3 pages of holograph research notes by RBN.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Blanche Dunn, 3 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Bert Williams, 3 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript carbon copy. Acidic paper, age-tanned. Edges chiped.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Mary Simpson Washington, 3 Leaves + 2 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript carbon copy. Acidic paper, age-tanned (3 pp.). Together with a tow-page typescript of an earlier version.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Marcus Garvey, 6 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Charles Sidney Gilpin, 4 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "And Robert[Schlick], Who is White (WPA), 2 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript ribbon copy. Acidic, age-tanned paper. Missing a middle page.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Sufi (Sufi Abdul Hamid) (The Black Hitler of Harlem), 7 Leaves + 1 Leaf (Box 20)
    Typescript ribbon copy. Acidic, age-tanned paper.. Incomplete. With typewritten notes re Sufi and Gilpin, and holograph notes re Sufi.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): Emancipation, 3 Leaves (Box 20)
    Acidic, age-tanned paper.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "On Fred. Douglass, 2 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Harriet Tubman, 4 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Incident Attandant Upon Uncle Tom's Cabin, 9 Leaves (Box 20)
    Holograph manuscript (3 pp.), Ribbon typescript (3 pp.), Later carbon (3 pp.)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Fisk Jubilee Singers" [title supplied], 5 Leaves (Box 20)
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Uncle Tom's Cabin in Newj York, 8 Leaves (Box 20)
    Ribbon copy with a few corrections (4 pp.), & later carbon (4 pp.) on acidic, age-tanned paper.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "And Rose (McClendon), 3 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript, ribbon copy
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Notes on New York Negroes and Negro New York: On John Marrant, 7 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript, ribbon copy (5 pp.) & incomplete carbon (2 pp.).
  - Pattern for Future Dirges, ca. 1949-51; 28 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. SIGNED by Nugent.
  - Pattern for Future Dirges, 30 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript, ribbon copy (28 pp. + title page and heavy paper cover page). Stains.
  - Pattern for Future Dirges, 1947; 32 Leaves (Box 20)
    Typescript, carbon copy. Dated title page. 28 pp. (missing the last page). Handwritten syllable count on many pages. Stains. + Incomplete 4-page typescript, carbon copy.
  - Pattern for Future Dirges, 1970s; 54 Leaves (Box 20)
    1. 28-page typescript, ribbon copy, with the rhyme pattern pencilled in on the first page in holograph. 2. 26-page typescript, ribbon copy, with title page dedication to "A. D'A. Missing sonnets 26-28.
  - Pattern for Future Dirges--Notes, 1 Leaf (Box 20)
    Holograph notes. Acidic, tanned paper. Stains.
  - Cabaguil, ca 1945; 6 Leaves (Box 20)
    1. 3-page typescript, carbon copy, in Spanish with interlinear holograph translation in Nugent's hand. 2. 3-page holograph manuscript of the English translation, not in Nugent's hand. Incomplete.
  - Lispeth/ Stuartt/ Gino, 3 Leaves (ca 5" x 7") (Box 21)
    Typed notes for a novel or novella. Incomplete, pp. 2-4 only. The characters are based on recognizable friends of Nugent's: Lispeth being Louise Paul; Gino probably Geroge Giordano.
  - Hughes & Locke, 1 Leaf (Box 21)
    Sketch of meeting Langston Hughes with remarks about Alain Locke. Typescript, ribbon copy. Paper stained, wrinkled & torn.
  - For Langston... Sincerely (For Marty Wagner), 7 Leaves (Box 21)
    3-page typescript, ribbon copy with holograph corrections + 4-page typeset galley proof (including a title page).
  - Cartoon Captions, 11 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. A few lines per page. Apparently incomplete.
  - Drahcir Stories, 5 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. "Plot for a Story [The Clown]" (2 pp.) + "Paradise
  - Risus [Richtus?] Sardonicus: A Narrative Fragment [Poem], 40 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. Stains
  - Risus [Richtus?] Sardonicus: A Vintage Narrative: circa '42 [Poem], 34 Leaves + 2 Cover Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. A few holograph corrections. Apparently incomplete. Stains.
  - Risus [Richtus?] Sardonicus, 27 Leaves (Box 21)
    Fragments of various typed versions.
  - Journal of an Affair [Title Supplied], 16 Leaves. (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. 31 pages (verso & recto). Heavyweight paper.
  - Writings by Others, 4 Leaves (Box 21)
    Fragments
  - LEWLULU--One Act Play by Pedro Juan Pietri And Nobody Else, 50 Leaves (Box 21)
    Xerox copy. Probably by Nugent. But maybe not.
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Incident to David Ruggles, 1 Leaf (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy with holograph corrections
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Urges Negroes to Revolt/Colored Pastor Would Stop Lynching With Bullets, 2 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript of a NY Times article of 4 March 1904
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): "Report on Plan to Colonize P.I. with Negroes, 8 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. Acidic, age-tanned paper
  - Harlem Personalities & Black History (WPA): Unidentified Fragments, 6 Leaves (Box 21)
  - Negro in New York, The (WPA): Chapter 9 -- The Civil War, 28 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, carbon copy on vellum.
  - Negro in New York, The (WPA): Chapter 10 -- The Luxury of Being Black, 30 Leaves (Box 21)
  - Negro in New York, The (WPA): Chapter 12, 5 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. Age-tanned. Incomplete.
  - Negro in New York, The (WPA): Fragments, 19 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, carbon copies on cellum
  - Automat, The -- An Impression ( WPA?), 6 Leaves (Box 21)
    Typescript, ribbon copy on bond.
  - Worm's End, ca 1935; 24 Photostats, 23 + 2 Leaves (Box 22)
  - Each Man Needs a Friend, 1 Leaf (Box 22)
    A saying about friendship that Nugent in conversation attributed to E. M. Forster, at whose home Nugent spent a weekend in 1929.
  - d. p. on the g. and f. of an e. i. by an o. p., 1950-51; 42 Leaves (Box 22)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. Incomplete. Stains on some pages.
  - Harlem: A Cultural Capitol, ca1968-71; 36 Leaves (Box 22)
  - Harlem: A Cultural Capitol, ca 1968-71; 30 + 30 Leaves (Box 22)
    Lacking the title page and preliminary overview, but otherwise complete. Ribbon copy on lightly age-toned paper. Together with a Xerox copy.
  - Harlem: A Cultural Capitol (Outline), ca 1968-71; 16 + 7 Leaves (Box 22)
    Probably the final version. Ribbon copy on bond together with a carbon, both incomplete.
  - Harlem: A Cultural Capitol (Outline), ca 1968-71; 22 Leaves (Box 22)
    Carbon copy on lightly tanned paper. Incomplete. Probably an early version.
  - Harlem: A Cultural Capitol (Outline), ca 130 Leaves (estimated) (Box 22)
    Fragments & Misc Related Materials
  - Interview With L---------, June 2, 1978; 12 Leaves (Box 22)
    Xerox copy. No internally missing pages, but incomplete.
  - Lady Bradstreet [Title Supplied], ca 1931; 12 Leaves (Box 23)
    A parody of Carl Van Vechten's writing. The verso of the last leaf contains notes for the Bible Stories. Leaves from a notebook. Holograph. Paper age-tanned and fragile. Edges stained with cat urine. Pages individually protected in polyester folders.
  - I Am Twenty Five [Title Supplied], ca 1931; 2 Leaves (Box 23)
    Holograph manuscript. Leaves from a notebook. Paper age-tanned and fragile. Edges stained with cat urine. Leaves individually protected in polyester folders.
  - Bible Stories: Tree With Kerioth Fruit, ca 1931; 21 Leaves (Box 23)
  - Bible Stories: Notes, ca 1931; 6 Leaves (Box 23)
    Holograph notes. Leaves from a notebook. Paper age-tanned and fragile. Edges stained with cat urine. Leaves individually protected in polyester folders.
  - Bible Stories: Slender Length of Beauty, ca 1931; 21 Leaves (Box 23)
  - Bible Stories: Beyond, Where the Star Stood Still, ca 1931; 22 Leaves (Box 23)
  - Bible Stories: The Now Discordant Song of Bells, ca 1931; 25 Leaves (Box 23)
  - Bible Stories: Notes & Fragments, 8 Leaves (Box 24)
  - Bible Stories: Cover, 1 Leaf (Box 24)
    Cover of a booklet, "Saffron and Calamous: Bible Stories by Richard Bruce Nugent" Typed on a large label pasted to heavy colored stock.
  - Bible Stories: Beyond Where the Star Stood Still, 12 Leaves + 2 Leaves (Box 24)
    Typescript on bond. Age-tanned around the edges. Two leaves from an apparently earlier version.
  - Bible Stories: The Now Discordant Song of Bells, 15 Leaves (Box 24)
    Typescript on bond. Age-tanned around the edges. SIGNED BY NUGENT
  - Bible Stories: Slender Length of Beauty, 14 Leaves (Box 24)
    Typescript on bond. Age-tanned around the edges. Some stains. SIGNED BY NUGENT
  - Bible Stories: Slender Length of Beauty, 13 Leaves (Box 24)
    Typescript on bond. Stains. Missing the last page.
  - Bible Stories: Tree With Kerioth Fruit, 6 Leaves + 2 Leaves (Box 24)
    Two incomplete typescripts, one with holograph corrections.
  - Bible Stories: Tunic With a Thousand Pleats, 17 Leaves (Box 24)
    Typescript on bond. Age-tanned around the edges. Stains.
  - Bible Stories: Tunic With a Thousand Pleats, 8 Leaves (Box 24)
    Photocopy of page proofs from the unpublished Gumby Book Studio Quarterly. (Gumby Scrapbook 37, Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University)
  - Cabaguil: A Ballet, by Mario Monteforte-Toledo. English Version by Bruce Nugent, pp. 1-15. Together with earlier drafts and associated materials, 1944; ca 49 leaves. Carbon copies withholograph corrections; some notes in holograph. (Box 24)
  - Magnolia Scent -- A Modern Play in Three Acts" by Helen Winner and Richard Bruce Nugent, 1946; ca. 102 leaves. Carbon copy on vellum (Box 24)
  - SMOKE, LILIES & JADE, pp. 30-31; "Father's Death, ca 1926; 3 leaves. Two are holograph in ink on lined paper. Lower corner stained. The third is typed. (Box 24)
    The holograph leaves are pages from a missing manuscript. The material does not appear in the published version. The typed leaf contains part of the description of Nugent's father's death--a variant of the published ;version.
  - Notes, 1 Spiral Notebook + 8 Leaves (Box 25)
    Notes for classes taken/given by Nugent. Costume design, teaching materials
  - Notebooks, 3 Spiral Secretarial Notebooks+7 Notecards (Box 25)
    Notes for classes taken/given by Nugent-- Italian language; Greek language. Fragment from Ciao. Letters to Antonio D'Ambrosio for translation.
  - Notebook, 1 Composition Book (Box 25)
    Miscellaneous fragments. A few sketches. Many blank pages.
  - Notebooks, 4 Stenographer's Notebooks (Box 25)
    Italian language; a few poems & sketches. Many blank pages.
  - Notebook Pages, 7 Leaves (Box 25)
    From a notebook entitled "Grab Bag". Blank pages discarded. Architectural sketch, fragment from Ciao, names from Harlem history.
  - Summary History of the Harlem Cultural Council, 1968; 2 Items (Box 25)
    1. Typescript, carbon copy. (3 leaves) 2. Typescript, ribbon copy (4 leaves). Initialled by Nugent on the last page.
  - Ballet Paradox, ca 1932; 5 Leaves (Box 26)
    A concept document for a ballet. Holograph on lined, age-toned paper.
  - Hatch-Billops Interview, 4/4/1982; 28 Leaves, 1 Brochure (Box 26)
    Photocopy of the typescript for the interview published in Artists & Influences 1982 by the Hatch-Billops Collection, together with a brochure advertising the publication.
  - Poem: "You Think To Shame Me" [Title supplied], 10 Leaves (Box 26)
    Typescript, ribbon copy, on lightweight, age-toned paper (legal size)
  - This is the Day, 5 Leaves (Box 26)
    An erotic fantasy with autobiographical roots. Outline notes and 2 holograph manuscript pages.
  - This is the Day, 25 Leaves (Box 26)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. Incomplete; only partially sorted.
  - This is the Day, 11 Leaves (Box 26)
    Typescript, ribbon copy. Incomplete; only partially sorted. Some leaves stained and/or badly torn.
  - Zographos [Zografos; Zograpos], 1970s; 57 Leaves (Box 26)
  - Zographos [Zografos; Zograpos], 1970s; 12 Leaves (Box 26)
    Single incomplete typed pages
  - Zographos [Zografos; Zograpos], 1970s; ca 50 Leaves (Box 26)
    Holograph notes and single manuscript pages
  - Zographos [Zografos; Zograpos], 1970s; ca 10 Leaves (Box 26)
    Typed manuscript leaves & notes in Italian; incomplete and mostly unsorted.
  - Lighting FIRE!!, 1982; Several Items (Box 26)
    3-page typed manuscript by Nugent, photocopy with holograph corrections by Wirth, revised version typed by Wirth with holograph corrections, first galley proof.
  - Ciao Holograph Leaves (Box 27)
  - Il Romano Fatale -- Diary Form, 4 Holograph Leaves (Box 27)
    Semi-autobiographal narrative relating to Ciao
  - Square of the Circle -- Holograph Manuscript Fragments, 4 Leaves (Box 27)
  - Uranus in Cancer -- Holograph Fragments, ca 11 Leaves (Box 27)
  - Stuartt Geneology -- Holograph Notes, 6 Leaves (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous Typed Manuscript Pages, ca 40 Leaves (Box 27)
    Unsorted typescript pages